{"tossups": [{"question": "A man from this ethnic group defended his citizenship in U.S. v Ark, whose large-scale immigration was enabled by the Burlingame-Seward Treaty. Violence against these people occurred in Los Angeles and Wallowa County, Oregon, while at least 28 of these people died during a massacre in (*) Rock Springs, Wyoming, Large numbers of these people labored to construct the Transcontinental Railroad, and this group was notably victimized by California\u2019s Anti-Coolie Act and a namesake \u201cExclusion\u201d Act. For ten points, name this U.S. immigrant group which emmigrated from the world\u2019s largest country.", "answer": "Chinese Americans (prompt on \u201cChinese\u201d)", "subcategory": "History American", "category": "History"}, {"question": "One painting from this period shows an inmate at the Saint-Lazare prison hospital and is called Woman with Folded Arms. A painting from this period called The Tragedy depicts a homeless family on a beach. The death of Carlos Casagemas sparked this movement whose common subjects include drunks, beggars, and prostitutes painted in (*) somber colors. The composition, style, and namesake color of this period is exemplified by a depiction of a blind man in rags entitled The Old Guitarist. For 10 points, name this depressive period in the art of Pablo Picasso followed by the Rose Period.", "answer": "Picasso\u2019s Blue Period", "subcategory": "Fine Arts Visual", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This color precipitate occurs in the triiodomethane reaction of ketones. The heating of nitric acid with tryptophan produces xanthoproteic acid, a substance of this color. The section of the NFPA safety diamond with this color indicates chemical reactivity. When there is a positive result, this is the color of Ellman\u2019s reagent and (*) Nessler\u2019s reagent. Below pH 6.8, the indicator phenol red is this color, which is also seen in the Fraunhofer line of helium and in the flame test of sodium. For 10 points, name this color of crystalline sulfur.", "answer": "yellow (accept equivalents)", "subcategory": "Science Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "This man sailed for the Muscovy Company in his first voyage. Abacuk Pricket\u2019s diary is an important source for information on this man\u2019s final days, while his ghost is featured in Washington Irving\u2019s Rip Van Winkle. This captain of the (*) Hopewell laid the foundation for the creation of New Netherland through a 1609 exploration. In this man\u2019s final voyage, the crew of his ship Discovery mutinied and set him and his son adrift. For ten points, name this English explorer and captain of the Half Moon with a namesake bay in northeast Canada.", "answer": "Henry Hudson", "subcategory": "History American", "category": "History"}, {"question": "This thinker discussed the homologous nature of plant organs in one work and human color perception in another. Those two works are Metamorphosis of Plants and Theory of Colors. This author wrote a novel about Eduard and Charlotte and their friends the Captain and Ottilie that emulates a double displacement reaction. This author also wrote about a man who (*) takes his own life after realizing he can never love Charlotte. This author\u2019s most notable work centers on the title character\u2019s deal with Mephistopheles to gain the ability to perform magic. For ten points, name this German author of Elective Affinities, The Sorrows of Young Werther, and Faust.", "answer": ": Johann Wolfgang von Goethe", "subcategory": "Literature European", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This region experienced the First and Second Servile Wars, and was briefly ruled by Sextus Pompey. The fall of Taormina completed the Muslim conquest of this region, which was in turn conquered by Roger Bosso. The Expedition of the Thousand targeted a kingdom named for (*) two of this region, and this region\u2019s namesake \u201cVespers\u201d revolted against France in the thirteenth century. Nicias led a disastrous Athenian expedition to capture this island, and victory in the First Punic War gave Rome hegemony over it. For ten points, name this large Mediterranean island south of the Italian peninsula.", "answer": "Sicily", "subcategory": "History Classical", "category": "History"}, {"question": "This character once lit a fire that woke up an animal which he had previously thought to be an island. After this character was captured by dwarves on a different adventure, a one-eyed giant ate members of his crew. This man\u2019s ship was destroyed by (*) rocs throwing rocks. In that same voyage, this character\u2019s fifth, he met and killed the old man of the sea. On this man\u2019s seventh and final voyage, he is given enough ivory to keep him rich forever. For ten points, name this character who appears in One Thousand and One Nights, a merchant from the city of Baghdad.", "answer": "Sinbad the Sailor", "subcategory": "Literature World", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This man\u2019s allies include Mutt Williams, Sallah, and Marion Ravenwood. In one film, this character frees children from a brutal Thuggee cult, while in another this man and Mac McHale are kidnapped by Irina Spalko. In one famous scene, this character dispatches with a (*) sword-swinging opponent by just shooting him. In that same movie, this hero flees from a giant boulder to steal a South American idol. For ten points, name this whip-wielding archaeologist played by Harrison Ford and found in such films as Temple of Doom and Raiders of the Lost Ark.", "answer": "Indiana Jones (prompt on partial answer)", "category": "Trash"}, {"question": "Following this experiment, it was predicted that s is proportional to Q sub n squared and inversely proportional to the sine of phi over two to the fourth power. A later version of this experiment uses a conical glass tube sealed with mica containing \u201cradium emanation\u201d and bismuth-214 to emit particles at a (*) zinc sulfide screen. A scintillator was used to count the flashes of light created by the backward scattering of alpha particles in this experiment, which disproved J. J. Thomson\u2019s plum-pudding model of the atom. For 10 points, name this experiment, which led to the discovery of a positively charged nucleus.", "answer": "Rutherford experiment (accept Gold Foil experiment or Geiger\u2013Marsden experiment)", "subcategory": "Science Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "The early history of these people is recorded in the Anitta Text. The Chief of the Wine Stewards was a powerful office in this civilization, whose laws permitted execution only for murder, theft, or bestiality. This empire was toppled during the Bronze Age collapse, during which this kingdom\u2019s capital at (*) Hattusa was razed. One king of this civilization, Hattusili III, signed one of history\u2019s earliest peace treaties following this empire\u2019s defeat in the largest chariot battle ever. For ten points, name this ancient Anatolian civilization which fought against Ramses II of Egypt at the Battle of Kadesh.", "answer": "Hittites HALFTIME", "subcategory": "History Classical", "category": "History"}, {"question": "This character knows that the statement \u201cIf You Break the Law, You Can\u2019t Win!\u201d is false because a man can afford to pay off the prosecutors. This character kills a rat with a skillet after it appears in the house this character shares with Vera and Buddy. After a character goes missing, this character writes a ransom note signed (*) \u201cRed\u201d and demands $10,000. This character decapitates a corpse in order to stuff it into the furnace. That body was that of Mary Dalton, who this character had accidentally smothered with a pillow. For ten points, name this character, the protagonist of Richard Wright\u2019s Native Son.", "answer": "Bigger Thomas (prompt on partial answer)", "subcategory": "Literature American", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "In a short story by Heinrich Boll, this is celebrated every day of the year in order to keep Aunt Milla from screaming hysterically. In a Joyce work set on this day, money is shoved into the hands of the maid Lily by Gabriel Conroy during a party for this holiday. That story is (*) \u201cThe Dead.\u201d In a Hans Christian Andersen story, this day is the happiest day of a character\u2019s life, because it is decorated with a golden star and candles. That character is the story\u2019s namesake \u201cFir-Tree\u201d. For ten points, name this holiday that features three ghosts who haunt Ebeneezer Scrooge in a Charles Dickens work and is celebrated on December 25th.", "answer": "Christmas", "subcategory": "Literature European", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "The Jacobi identity is one condition that can be placed on entities that lack this property, and it is satisfied by the Lie bracket operation. The primary difference between a group and a quasigroup is that a quasigroup lacks this property, which all convergent infinite series posses. Unlike quaternions, (*) octonions lack this property for multiplication. Although it is not commutativity, operators that lack this property include subtraction and division. For 10 points, name this property which states that the order in which consecutive occurrences of certain binary operations are carried out will not affect the result of an expression.", "answer": "associativity (accept associative property)", "subcategory": "Science Math", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "In one of this man's works, the Astrologer commands the title animal to kill the husband of the Queen of Shemakha. This man wrote the slavic-themed opera Mlada, and another of his work\u2019s includes the \u201cDance of the Tumblers\u201d and tells how Mizgir\u2019s love causes the (*) Snow Maiden to melt. One orchestral suite by this man includes the movements \u201cFestival at Baghdad\u201d and \u201cThe Sea and Sinbad\u2019s Ship\u201d and was inspired by the Arabian Nights. For 10 points, name this Russian composer of The Golden Cockerel whose opera The Tale of Tsar Saltan includes the \u201cFlight of the Bumblebee\u201d.", "answer": "Nikolai Rimsky-Korsakov (do not accept partial last name)", "subcategory": "Fine Arts Auditory", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This complex contains the iconic Court of the Myrtles. The Hall of the Ambassadors is the largest room in this structure from which Washington Irving wrote a namesake book of tales. A walkway connected this complex to the Generalife Palace and this structure's many English elms were introduced during the Peninsular War. This palace includes the (*) Court of the Lions with its characteristic arches and served as the heart of the Nasrid Dynasty before falling to Ferdinand and Isabella. For ten points, name this Islamic fortress and palace complex which overlooks Granada.", "answer": "the Alhambra", "subcategory": "Fine Arts Other", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "An experiment involving this organism used the liquid medium DM25. That long-term evolution experiment was conducted by Richard Lenski. Conjugation was first described by Tatum and Lederberg using this organism. T2 bacteriophages labelled with phosphorus and sulfur infected this organism in the (*) Hershey\u2013Chase experiments, while another experiment using this organism and two nitrogen isotopes showed that DNA replication was semiconservative and was conducted by Meselson and Stahl. Glucose and galactose are cleaved using the lac operon, discovered by Jacob and Monod in this organism. For 10 points, name this gram-negative bacterium with serotype O157:H7 that can cause food poisoning.", "answer": "Escherichia coli", "subcategory": "Science Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "According to myth, two twin brothers encountered this figure when they went hunting too far east of their home, and in another, this figure rescued a group of people from inside a giant. In another myth, this figure tells a giant that he can break his leg and then heal it in order to make the giant run faster, but he ends up just breaking it. This figure caused (*) Changing Bear to become evil and kill her brothers. For 10 points, name this trickster god of North American mythology who shares many mythological traits with Raven.", "answer": "Coyote", "category": "Mythology"}, {"question": "One collection of works of this type includes \u201cHelen\u2019s Exile\u201d and \u201cSummer in Algiers.\u201d Albert Camus also wrote \u201cThe Myth of Sisyphus\u201d in this format, which is also used in Baldassare Castiglione\u2019s Book of the Courtier. Another work in this form distinguishes primary and secondary qualities in order to argue that the mind begins as a (*) tabula rasa. The name of this format was coined from the French word \u201cto try\u201d by Michel de Montaigne. For 10 points, name this argumentative form of philosophical writing used by John Locke in his one \u201cConcerning Human Understanding.\u201d", "answer": "essay (prompt on \u201cpaper\u201d)", "category": "Philosophy"}, {"question": "Every spring, this territory celebrates a festival featuring three 60-foot towers of buns. Carrie Lam serves as chief executive of this region often symbolized with the Bauhinia orchid. The International Commerce Centre and many other major landmarks can be found within this territory\u2019s Kowloon Peninsula, and the Pearl River Delta separates it from (*) Macau. Located just south of Shenzhen, this region has been governed by the \u201cOne Country, Two Systems\u201d policy since it was transferred from British rule in 1997. For ten points, name this densely-populated Special Administrative Region in southern China.", "answer": "Hong Kong (accept Xiang Gang)", "category": "Geography"}, {"question": "Edgar Allan Poe named one of his poems after the seventh section of this work, which is called \u201cThe Heights\u201d. One section of this text called \u201cSpoils of War\u201d describes the 7th century Battle of Badr, and this text is divided into sections called juz so that it can be read in (*) thirty days. Portions of this book are called surahs like \u201cThe Cow,\u201d while declares that one must fast during a certain month. This text, along with the Hadith, forms the basis of Sharia law. For 10 points, name this book that was revealed by Gabriel to Muhammad, the holy book of Islam.", "answer": "Quran (or Koran)", "category": "Religion"}, {"question": "This man famously visited a farm owned by Roswell Garst. This ally of Lazar Kaganovich sanctioned the execution of Lavrentiy Beria and organized the unsuccessful Virgin Lands campaign. This leader attracted controversy by asserting \u201cWe will bury you\u201d and he notably banged his (*) shoe on a desk during a speech before the UN. After assuming his highest office, this man delivered the \u201cSecret Speech\u201d and later faced off against Richard Nixon in the \u201cKitchen Debate.\u201d For ten points, name this Soviet premier and successor to Stalin who led the USSR during the Cuban Missile Crisis.", "answer": "Nikita Khrushchev Bonuses", "subcategory": "History American", "category": "History"}], "bonuses": [{"leadin": "This man paid his way through Hampton Institute by working as a janitor. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Booker T. Washington", "bucket", "The White House"], "parts": ["Name this civil rights leader of the early 20th century and first president of the Tuskegee Institute. This man advocated for gradual social change in contrast to W.E.B. Du Bois.", "In his \u201cAtlanta Exposition\u201d Address, Washington encouraged black Americans to \u201ccast down\u201d this object and view hard work and education as the pathway to equality.", "In 1901, Washington dined with Teddy Roosevelt in this building, becoming the first African American to formally do so. After a backlash, no other black American was invited to dine in this building for nearly 30 years."], "subcategory": "History American", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "James Maxwell first derived this law in the paper \u201cOn Physical Lines of Force.\u201d For 10 points each:", "answers": ["Amp\u00e8re's circuital law", "displacement current (do not accept or prompt on \u201ccurrent\u201d)", "superconductors"], "parts": ["Name this law that states that in a closed loop, the line integral of the magnetic field is proportional to the enclosed current.", "Maxwell added this term, symbolized J, to Amp\u00e8re's law to account for a time-varying electric field.", "Amp\u00e8re's law is used to derive the second London equation, which includes a term for the London penetration depth of these materials. These materials may exhibit the Josephson Effect."], "subcategory": "Science Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "The death of President Francisco Solano L\u00f3pez marked the end of this war. For ten points each:", "answers": ["War of the Triple Alliance", "Brazil", "slavery"], "parts": ["Name this destructive South American conflict in which a namesake coalition crushed Paraguay and claimed much of its territory.", "The Triple Alliance consisted of Argentina, Uruguay, and this large Amazonian nation led by Emperor Pedro II.", "Success in the War of the Triple Alliance significantly contributed to the decline of this institution in Brazil, with many of its victims being impressed into military service."], "subcategory": "History World", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "Consider the reaction AgNO<sub>3</sub> + NaCl \u2192 AgCl + NaNO<sub>3</sub>. For 10 points each:", "answers": ["precipitation reaction (accept precipitate)", "spectator ions", "solubility product constant (accept Ksp)"], "parts": ["This is an example of what type of reaction, in which a solid salt forms from the combination of two solutions with soluble ions?", "In this reaction, NO3- and Na+ act as this type of ion. This type of ion remains unchanged during the reaction.", "Silver chloride has a value of 1.8\u00d710\u201310 for this constant. For the aforementioned precipitation reaction, this value is the product of the concentration of Ag and the concentration of Cl."], "subcategory": "Science Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "After decades of conflict, the French Wars of Religion climaxed with the enticingly titled War of the Three Henrys. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Huguenots", "House of Guise", "Edict of Nantes"], "parts": ["The War of the Three Henrys pitted Catholics against these French Protestants, led by Henry of Navarre. 15 years earlier, up to 30,000 of these people were killed during the St. Bartholomew's Day massacre.", "The Huguenots\u2019 chief enemy was a Henry from this French house. Both that Henry and a powerful cardinal from this house were assassinated on the orders of King Henry III.", "Though Henry of Navarre emerged as the last Henry standing, he converted to Catholicism to claim the French crown. However, Henry promulgated this edict giving Huguenots considerable religious freedom."], "subcategory": "History European", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "Answer the following questions about recent covers of <em>The New Yorker</em> magazine. For ten points each:", "answers": ["clown", "sitting on a stoop (accept porch sitting or anything to that effect)", "Kim Jong Un"], "parts": ["The October 23 edition of The New Yorker depicted Donald Trump as one of these characters. Bill Skarsg\u00e5rd plays one of these characters named Pennywise in the 2017 film It.", "The New Yorker\u2019s September 25 cover contained a painting of a father and daughter performing this action. Activist author Jane Jacobs asserted that this action helps prevent urban crime.", "Half of this man\u2019s head appears on The New Yorker\u2019s September 7 cover. Two weeks later, this man referred to one international opponent as \u201cthe mentally deranged U.S. dotard.\u201d"], "category": "Trash"}, {"leadin": "This brother of Vili and Ve gets information from his ravens Huginn and Muninn, and he rides the eight-legged horse Sleipnir. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Odin", "eye", "Ratatoskr"], "parts": ["Name this chief Norse god who will be eaten by Fenrir during Ragnarok.", "Odin sacrificed this part of his body at Mimir\u2019s Spring in order to drink and gain the world\u2019s knowledge.", "Mimir\u2019s Spring is located at the base of the world tree Yggdrasil, home to this squirrel who carrys messages from the eagle at the tree\u2019s top to the dragon below its roots."], "category": "Mythology"}, {"leadin": "In this play, two strangers, Goldberg and McCann, arrive in the residence of the protagonist and stage the title event. For ten points each:", "answers": ["The Birthday Party", "Harold Pinter", "the Kettle"], "parts": ["Name this play set in a rundown boarding house occupied by a pianist named Stanley Weber.", "This playwright wrote The Birthday Party and other \u201ccomedies of menace.\u201d This man also wrote The Dumb Waiter.", "In the play The Dumb Waiter, Gus and Ben argue about whether this object should be \u201cturned on\u201d or \u201cput on.\u201d"], "subcategory": "Literature British", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "This poem begins with the lines \u201cA willow of crystal a poplar of water / a pillar of fountain by the wind drawn over.\u201d For ten points each:", "answers": ["\u201cSunstone\u201d", "Octavio Paz", "Hanuman"], "parts": ["Name this surrealist poem whose 584 lines mimic the Aztec Calendar.", "This Mexican author wrote \u201cSunstone,\u201d as well as an extended essay titled The Labyrinth of Solitude.", "Paz also wrote about a journey to Galta, India, home of a shrine to this Monkey Grammarian."], "subcategory": "Literature World", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "This man attempted to link Scandinavian myth with a hypothetical civilization in Azerbaijan. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Thor Heyerdahl", "Kon-Tiki", "Easter Island"], "parts": ["Name this Norwegian ethnographer who sailed across the Pacific to demonstrate the capacity of ancient seafaring. This man used his experiences to support several theories of transoceanic cultural exchange.", "Heyerdahl crossed the Pacific in this raft made out of 9 balsa logs and named for the Incan sun god.", "In another expedition, Heyerdahl travelled to this island to investigate its characteristic moai heads. Heyerdahl associated this island depopulation to a long ago civil war among the Rapa Nui people."], "category": "Social Science"}, {"leadin": "Answer the following questions about where El Dorado was supposed to be. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Walter Raleigh", "Orinoco River", "Lake Parime"], "parts": ["This English gentleman searched for El Dorado in Guyana but had no more success there than in setting up his lost colony of Roanoke. This favorite of Queen Elizabeth was executed by her successor, James I.", "The explorations of Raleigh and other would-be discoverers of El Dorado frequently traversed this great river of Venezuela.", "According to legend, El Dorado is located by this mythic body of water. Modern archaeologists have suggested that this lake existed in the Age of Exploration but has since dried up."], "category": "Geography"}, {"leadin": "Schools of this belief system include Soto and Obaku. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Zen Buddhism (prompt on \u201cMahayana Buddhism\u201d)", "koans", "satori"], "parts": ["Name this branch of Buddhism popular in Japan which emphasizes calmness and meditation.", "These questions and statements are used to test a person\u2019s understanding of Zen. These ideas are recorded in texts like The Blue Cliff Record and include \u201cWhat is the sound of one hand clapping?\u201d", "Adherents of Zen Buddhism strive toward this state of sudden enlightenment. It is often contrasted with kensh\u014d."], "subcategory": "Religion East Asian", "category": "Religion"}, {"leadin": "The Sherman paradox concerns the anomalous pattern of inheritance in one disease of this structure. For 10 points each:", "answers": ["X chromosome (prompt on \u201cfragile X syndrome\u201d)", "Barr body (accept drumstick)", "Turner syndrome"], "parts": ["Name these structures that become \u201cfragile\u201d due to the expansion of CGG triplet repeats.", "Lyonization inactivates an X chromosome, which is then referred to by this term. Men with Klinefelter\u2019s syndrome have one of these structures.", "The lack of an X chromosome in females causes this condition, symbolized 45,X. Symptoms of this disorder include coarctation of the aorta and a webbed neck."], "subcategory": "Science Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "This work, based on 11 pieces by Victor Hartmann, was orchestrated for the full orchestra by Maurice Ravel. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Pictures at an Exhibition", "Modest Mussorgsky", "Promenade"], "parts": ["Name this suite that includes movements such as \u201cThe Gnome,\u201d and \u201cThe Old Castle.\u201d It describes walking between displays at a museum.", "This composer wrote Pictures at an Exhibition, originally a piano composition.", "This in the name of the theme that plays between many of the movements. It appears five times throughout the piece."], "subcategory": "Fine Arts Auditory", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"leadin": "In this film, Ugarte acquires two \u201cletters of transit\u201d which he passes off to the protagonist. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Casablanca", "Rick Blaine", "Heinrich Strasser"], "parts": ["Name this superbly-quotable 1943 film set during World War Two in Morocco\u2019s largest city.", "This protagonist of Casablanca laments that \"of all the gin joints in all the towns in all the world,\u201d Ilsa Lund walked into his. At the end of the film, this man arranges for Ilsa and her husband Laszlo to flee the city.", "Blaine also shoots this man at the end of Casablanca. This Nazi major was pursuing Laszlo, a member of the Czech resistance."], "category": "Trash"}, {"leadin": "Answer the following questions about food in mathematics. For 10 points each:", "answers": ["bisection (accept cutting in half or other equivalents)", "Chicken McNuggets (or the Chicken McNugget Theorem)", "probability theory"], "parts": ["The pancake theorem is the two-dimensional version of the ham sandwich theorem, which states that it is possible to perform this process on an n-dimensional object using an n-minus-one dimensional hyperplane.", "A special case of the coin problem is named for this food because they were originally only sold in boxes of 6, 9, and 20. Using those values, the largest integer not described by this food is 43.", "The Chinese restaurant process, a process in this field of mathematics, concerns the likelihood of customers sitting at an occupied table. Bayes\u2019 theorem describes a conditional construct in this branch of mathematics."], "subcategory": "Science Math", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "The descendants of Genghis Khan, known as <em>genghisids</em>, accomplished a great many things in a great many places. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Kublai Khan", "Golden Horde", "Babur"], "parts": ["This grandson of Genghis founding the Yuan Dynasty of China, though his attempts to conquer Japan and Vietnam were unsuccessful. Samuel Taylor Coleridge penned a noted poem titled for this man.", "Another grandson of Genghis, Batu Khan, established this colorfully named empire stretching across Russia from the Danube to Siberia.", "This distant genghisid struggled to build a kingdom worthy of his ancestors, but finally found success in India and became the first Mughal emperor."], "subcategory": "History World", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "In this novel, the words \u201cA return after long wanderings\u201d are written on one character\u2019s tombstone, and \u201cHe wanted the kingdom of God on earth\u201d are written on another. For ten points each:", "answers": ["The Unbearable Lightness of Being", "Czechoslovakia (prompt on \u201cthe Czech Republic\u201d)", "kitsch"], "parts": ["Name this novel about the love of Tomas and Tereza amidst the Prague Spring.", "Milan Kundera, the author of The Unbearable Lightness of Being, experienced the Prague Spring first hand as a citizen of this country. This communist nation stripped Kundera of his citizenship in 1979.", "This is the German word Kundera uses to describe what Tomas fights against and what Sabina tries to escape. In English, this loanword translates as \u201ctackiness\u201d or \u201ccheesiness.\u201d"], "subcategory": "Literature European", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "Few works of art can capture nature\u2019s beauty like a landscape painting. For ten points each:", "answers": ["The Oxbow (accept View from Mount Holyoke, Northampton, Massachusetts, after a Thunderstorm)", "The Hay Wain", "Katsushika Hokusai"], "parts": ["This Thomas Cole landscape shows contrasts a story skyline with a calm river valley and takes its name from its curving geographic subject.", "This John Constable landscape shows Willy Lott's cottage in rural England and is named for the vehicle attempting to cross a river in its foreground.", "This Japanese artist painted 36 landscape views of Mount Fuji and also created The Great Wave off Kanagawa."], "subcategory": "Fine Arts Visual", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"leadin": "In this novel, the protagonist attempts to finish his missions, the number of which is always being raised by Colonel Cathcart. For ten points each:", "answers": ["Catch-22", "Joseph Heller", "M&amp;M Enterprises"], "parts": ["Name this novel that focuses on the military exploits of Captain John Yossarian during World War Two.", "This author of Catch-22 began writing the novel after he imagined the line, \u201cIt was love at first sight. The first time he saw the chaplain, Yossarian fell madly in love with him.\u201d", "This is the name of the syndicate run by Milo Minderbinder that sells chocolate covered cotton and eggs in Catch-22."], "subcategory": "Literature American", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "These animals perform the waggle dance to communicate the location of flowers with nectar and pollen. For 10 points each:", "answers": ["bees", "colony collapse disorder (accept CCD)", "mites (accept Acari)"], "parts": ["Name these insects in the clade Anthophila that includes a \u201cstingless honey\u201d one.", "Honeybees are affected by this phenomenon that occurs when many worker bees in a colony disappear, leaving behind nurse bees and a queen.", "Colony collapse disorder is postulated to be caused by the Acarapis or Varroa types of these arthropods. This group of arthropods does not include ticks."], "subcategory": "Science Biology", "category": "Science"}]}